Today is the Rigol 1000 E series
oscilloscope. It's It's a pretty new
series, not to be confused with the 1000
B series or the 1000 A series. They're
all different. So, just be careful. It's
a bit confusing. This is the This is the
DS1052E,
the 50 MHz
version.
It's also available in a mixed signal.
The mixed signal inputs go here, the
digital logic analyzer inputs, but this
is the basic unit. It's
bottom of the range, but it's really low
cost. It's incredibly low cost. I got
mine for 679 Australian dollars
delivered.
For you Yankee folk, that's less than
500 US dollars.
So, it's it's really a remarkable price
breakthrough.
For those who don't know Rigol, they've
been around for quite some time now, and
they manufacture low to mid-range scopes
among other gear. And I've used their
previous 5000 series oscilloscope, and
that was quite okay. It was much larger
than this, but this is the
one of their new models, and new
concept, the nice small model. And it's
even though they're their cheaper
oscilloscopes, they're really high
quality. This one's really quite
amazing. It just feels like a quality
scope.
All the button indents are really quite
high quality, the button presses, the
screen. The screen is really good.
It's a 320 by 240 quarter VGA, which is
pretty standard in this price bracket,
but it's got a nice bright LED
backlight. It's It's almost too bright,
really, and it's a It's a big step up
from their previous series.
Other things are a really nice carrying
handle, which locks into place. You've
got some really nice sturdy feet, which
snap out into position like that.
Uh it's got a USB host. Uh very
important. It allows you to plug in a
memory stick, get screen captures,
things like that. Uh it's really handy.
Um it's also got a um pass fail output
here, BNC. It's uh actually fully
isolated. And uh so you can use it for
um
uh
processors and things like that to
indicate
um automated pass fail test.
It's also got a USB input on the back.
Um it's got some PC remote control
software. You can control the scope
remotely.
Uh and so yeah, let's let's power it up.
And it takes a few seconds to boot up.
One of the um
I guess really the main annoying aspect
with it I have is that it does actually
have a fan. Uh it's not too loud, but
it's uh it's it's certainly not like a a
fanless unit unit like the TBS 210. So
that's one thing to consider, but it's
it's not too bad. You do get used to it.
Um as you can probably see, the screen
is nice and bright. Um
the the actual responses
uh the um
response to the controls and the
waveform updating is actually quite
fast. So it's it's really quite a usable
scope for the money. Um
course it's not as good as a real
high-end one, but uh
you know, for the money you can't go
wrong.
Now its big selling point, of course, is
that it's got a 1 meg point memory. Um
and 1 gig sample per second
sampling. Now Rigol were one of the
first Asian manufacturers to roll their
own 1 gig sample per second uh front
end, which is what they've actually
refined and they've finally used in
these units. They can go up to 2
gig sample in other models, but this
one's 1 gig sample.
Now the trade-off with that though is
that the 1 meg point memory is only
available at 500 meg samples or below,
which is still pretty good, but it's a
little bit that's something you should
watch out for. It's a little bit of a
trap. Um
at 1 gig sample though it's still got
15K of memory, which is still quite
large in comparison to most units. Now
there's really no other scope in the uh
on the market that can uh claim 1
uh meg point memory for this price
bracket. So, it's it really is a very
usable unit. It's got um automated
measurements, FFT as well, and um all
the fancy stuff, and it works quite
well. The firmware is really stable, and
um
and of course uh Rigol uh design and
manufacture Agilent's
or HP's low-end um scopes as well. So,
if it's good enough for HP, it's good
enough for me.
Definitely thumbs up the Rigol 1000E
series.